NESTOR FABIAN FIGUEROA GUTIERREZ FRONT END DEVELOPER

Profile:

Solid concepts in Front End Development, best practices in JS, css and HTML5. Searching every day for improvement. Experience in agile projects.

Contact: Dgn 30 35 sur 35 Envigado, Colombia

Email: nffigueroag@gmail.com

Skype: ffigueroa_ **Cel:** +57 320 389 3952

GitHub: : https://github.com/nffigueroa

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nffigueroag

Languages:

English/Spanish

Programming:

JavaScript, Html5, BootStrap, Bulma FrameWork, Mysql, Sql Server, Angular Framework, Vue Js, IONIC framework, ReactJs, SASS, css, GitHub, Gitlab, Web Component, React Native, Redux, Akita, Ngrx, NextJs,

Education:

2009 – 2011 Analysis and Development of Information System SENA

2012 - 2015 Systems engineering UNAD

Experience:

EPAM, Medellín, Colombia

Jan. 2022 - Currently working

- Application from scratch using Angular
- Custom UI library.

GLOBANT, Medellin, Colombia

Aug. 2020 - Dec. 2021

Senior Front end Developer

- Application from scratch, built on react js.
- For the styling styled components was used
- Redux State management implemented
- Creation of a dashboard in order to see the data collected by the client more user friendly.
- Monorepository nx.
- Build a custom ui library.
- Micro front ends
- Angular.

ENDAVA, Medellin, Colombia

May. 2019 - Aug. 2020

Senior Front end Developer

- Migration from Angular 4th to Angular 8th.
- Refactor the most important component in the app.
- Implementing State management
- React App , for internal projects in the company.
- Migration to new Authentication provider.

BOGOTA BANK, Bogota, Colombia

May. 2018- Apr. 2019

Front End Developer

- Project from scratch.
- Ux design used.
- Unit testing
- Ionic for the main app, also for a mobile app.
- First personal loan app for a bank released in Colombia.

Everis, Bogota, Colombia

Jul. 2017- Apr. 2018

FullStack Developer

- Migration legacy app, to new technologies.
- Ux design used.
- Unit testing
- Using the app the clients can recharge their accounts in order to fill their cars in the gas stations.

Praxis, Bogota, Colombia

Feb. 2016- Jul. 2017

Developer

- Supporting applications using .Net Technologies.
- It was an administrative app, which had integration with SAP.
- The logic was in the database using Stored Procedures.
- The App was built using the MVC pattern.